Najmeh Eshghi

najmeheshghi70@gmail.com, 416-460-5765, https://www.linkedin.com/in/najmeh-eshghi-05690552/

SUMMARY

STRUCTURAL EIT | TECHNICAL SUPPORT | CONSTRUCTION AND DESIGN

Civil Engineering graduate with work and academic focus on Structural Engineering including design, finite element analysis, construction, concrete casting, seismic assessment, examination, and retrofitting of structures

Experience with residential building construction. Employed as a co-op student to work on residential buildings under the supervision of site managers

Strong knowledge of building codes and standards (CSA, ASTM, ACI) (In addition to use of all these codes for my master's project, I taught these to undergraduate students preparing to become future EITs)

Volunteer to collaborate with different engineering and scientific consulting companies associated with Structural Laboratory of Lassonde School of Engineering to proceed their projects in their R&D sections

Well developed technical writing skills through article submission, thesis development, laboratory reports

Well developed English communication skills (I am told by colleagues a warm personality with great patience and good presentation ability)

Proficiency working with structural engineering software and can learn and apply my knowledge quickly with new software packages

Collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams, I have collaborated with specialists in these disciplinary areas: Mechanical, Geotechnical, Structural, and Environmental Engineering

Worked at Walmart, throughout first year of immigration to Canada, in a very fast-paced environment. Was recognised for my ability to remain calm under pressure dealing with constant interruptions and customer support requirements.

Fluently Bilingual: Farsi, English

SKILLS

AutoCAD | SAP2000 | ETABS | ATENA | VecTor | 3D Modeling | Finite Element Analysis | Microsoft Word | Microsoft Excel | PowerPoint | Customer Support | Valid full class Ontario Driver Licence

EDUCATION

York University, MSc. Structural Engineering, GPA A+, July 2018

Isfahan University of Technology, BSc, Civil Engineering, Iran, GPA A-, January 2015

EXPERIENCE

Lassonde School of Engineering, York University

Research/Teaching Assistant

09/2016 - Present

Assisting, supporting and technical resource for structural Engineering Professor with the design and development of new Fiber Reinforced Concrete theoretically and experimentally. Working with Finite Element software SAP2000, ATENA, VecTor to model concrete structural members. Working as a

Laboratory technician assistant on different projects on Steel and Synthetic Fiber Reinforced Concrete, shear concrete walls with shape memory alloys (SMAs), and Masonry structures. Working with laboratory equipment and performing examinations, testing, analysis, and set-ups. Instructing small and large groups of students (15-30-70) on the use of equipment, software, and technical concepts and the application of these in engineering.

Walmart, Saskatoon, Canada

Cashier 10/2013 – 04/2014

Learned how to deal with difficult customers in a diplomatic fashion in a high pressure fast paced environment. Ability to quickly troubleshoot problems with speed. Learned how to prioritize and multitask.

Noveen office of Engineering, Iran

Civil Engineering Co-op Student

09/2015 - 12/2015

Worked under the supervision of site managers in various construction activities. Performed various quality control tests on materials. Created plans, and sections using AutoCAD. Assisted in writing weekly and monthly project progress reports.

Eskan Office of Technical and Engineering, Iran

Part-Time CAD Technician

09/2011 - 01/2013

Worked closely with consultants and engineers in providing engineering drafting and design services. Communicated with customers for customizable drawings. Created CAD drawings from concept to final design, drawn to scale, suitably detailed to convey the necessary information required for approval. Checked and corrected any mistakes within the drawings.

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATES

Professional Engineers of Ontario (EIT application in process)

Ontario Society of Professional Engineers (OSPE)

Canadian Society for Civil Engineering (CSCE)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

LiveYourPotential STEM Ambassador in LYP, Toronto

An active member of GreenLiveToronto, City of Toronto

A volunteer member of Child Foundation for Education, Canada